Essence, this is what we're not going to do.
We're not going to try and disparage Amanda Seals for being a woman of principle,
for having character and courage, for laying respectability politics aside
in her relentless love of black people and her love of humanity.
Amanda Seals made a video talking about how she's not welcomed in black spaces
or celebrated in black spaces despite her work.
And then Essence commented on that very video and said,
we hear you and we love you.
We will do a better job at showing up for you and showing you that the love is real.
And then a few days later, they cleared a black woman to write an op-ed centering Amanda Seals,
talking about how likability is more important than being good at your job.
I mean, this is a thorough outlining about the importance of being liked.
It makes the claim that Amanda Seals doesn't have qualities that make her likable.
And the thing is, the writer acknowledges the history of black women and likability.
She talked about how black women have had to battle preconceived notions about the way they present
and then goes on to perpetuate that same anti-blackness by talking about likability,
saying, yeah, that history is true, but sometimes it's just us.
The writer said Amanda Seals consistently provokes uncomfortable yet necessary conversations
about everything from the Israeli occupation of Palestine.
Notice that's not what the writer called it.
Massage noir, racism, colorism, gender identity, and foreign policy.
Like, yes, Amanda Seals has a master's degree in African-American studies from Columbia University.
It makes sense that she's sharing this kind of information with the public.
We could really get into the layers of this,
the layers of how people lose their jobs and their livelihoods speaking up about injustice.
But literal abusers, black anti-black folks, known predators, do get the invite.
What, because they're likable?
Amanda Seals was never trying to be embraced by the Hollywood machine, as this writer suggested.
The use of the phrase Hollywood machine makes it seem like these aren't real people,
like these aren't black people.
And I know, like, some people are like, well, I don't understand.
It's like, you don't care what people think, but you want to be invited in their spaces.
And it's like, well, two things can be true at the same time, right?
Like, you can simultaneously be like, I need to do what needs to be done.
I need to say what needs to be said.
While also really feeling like, damn, it's unfortunate that these spaces that benefit
from that type of ardent challenging of systems that oppress it,
it's unfortunate that those places, that those places don't see, like, the value in what you do
to enhance those spaces.
She wanted to be embraced by her people, the people who she loved enough to dedicate her life
to the enhancement, to the entertainment, to the celebration, to the education of black people
in black culture.
So miss me with this nonsense about her not being liked.
I like people who have the courage to speak up about injustice and who don't prioritize being
agreeable over being ethical and empathetic.
I like people who, in the words of Nina Simone, have the courage to reflect the times in their
work.
An artist's duty, as far as I'm concerned, is to reflect the times.
I like people who will speak up for injustice even if everyone else remains silent.
I like people who have a heart for black people and who see the interconnectedness of our global
struggles.
I like people who recognize that the world we live in is broken.
People who are trying to do their part to shift it towards justice.
So while this writer has made it clear about her uncomfortability with those who agitate the
establishment even when they are right and have good intentions,
I'm grateful for folks like Amanda Seals who recognize that the establishment has never
really served us and are working to bring about change in bold and even prophetic ways.
I hope y'all know this is a cycle of history.
The prophetic voices who are crying out in the wilderness are always dismissed first and
then celebrated later.
But today, Amanda, I want you to know that we see you.
We're grateful for you.
And we're grateful for your contributions to this culture and to our people.
Love and liberation to you all.
And as always, like and follow for more content.